你肯定能用高山上的高山
You definitely can just go ahead and
use node alpine,
它是 80 兆字节，对于你的生产项目来说，一切都是这样做的。
it's 80 megabytes which is nothing, for
your production projects, always do that.
现在我们要做蠢事了，我们要去做自己的节点高山图像，因为我
Now we're gonna be dumb and we're gonna go
make our own node alpine image because I
想给你展示如何去做，如何设置这些不同的东西。
wanna show you how to do it,
how to set up all these different things.
所以我们要做的就是尝试和
So, what we're actually gonna try and
do is we're gonna try and
再把 80 兆字节进一步降低到 50 兆字节
get that 80 megabytes down even further so
you can get down to 50 megabytes.
我们来吧
Let's do it.
太荒谬了
Let's be ridiculous.
所以我们还在这里的高山 - linux ，我们在 12 - 高山上。
So we're still in alpine-linux here,
we're in 12-alpine right here.
我想让你做的不是说 12 号节点
And what I want you to do instead
of saying node 12-alpine,
我要你说阿尔卑斯 3.10
I want you to say alpine:3.10.
所以如果我来这里说医生检查阿尔卑斯 3.10
So, if I come in here and
say docker inspect alpine:3.10,
如果我把这个颜色给颜色就好了
this is way easier if
I just colorize that.
你可以在这里看到，这可能是字节，所以
You can see here,
this is in bytes maybe, so,
嗯，这个是五个点六兆字节。
yeah, this is five point
six-ish megabytes.
挺小的吧
Pretty small, right?
这比我们从其他国家来的 80 个要小得多
That's significantly smaller than the 80
that we had coming from our other
来自节点 alpine 的应用程序，它仅包含一些更有节点的节点
application from node alpine, and it just
includes some more node nicety stuff
就像一些你可能想要的东西一样
like some good idea stuff that
you're probably gonna want on there.
你只需要把这些东西包括在你最想要的东西上
Just include some of the stuff like that,
which for the most part you're gonna want.
节点源人员和
The node source people and
这种接近的形式是其他在这些事情上工作的公司。
the near form is the other company
that works on these kinda things.
好好保重，确保这些都尽量小。
Take pretty good care to make sure
that these are as small as possible.
所以相信他们是因为他们比你更可能在码头
So, trust them because they're probably
better at docker than maybe you are,
我不会这么说但他们肯定比我强
I'm not gonna say that, but
they're definitely better than I am.
如果你出于任何原因听我的话
And if you're for
whatever reason listening to me,
让我来代表他们的善意
so let me proxy that goodwill to them.
或者你不喜欢我，我不知道，你也可以恨他们。
Or maybe you don't like me, I don't know,
then you can hate them too.
所以我们要从这里的阿尔卑菠萝来
So, we're gonna do from alpine:3.10 here,
and what we're gonna
我们要说的是 RUN apk 是包经理的名字
do is we're gonna say RUN apk which
is the name of the package manager,
不是安卓的东西如果你是从安卓来的
not Android stuff,
if you're coming from Android.
APK 是 Alpine Package Manager。
APK is the Alpine Package Manager.
添加，我要说 --更新我，仅表示先运行更新，然后再进行
Add, I'm gonna say --update me which just
means run updates first before you, make
请确保您正在获取这些版本的最新版本，然后获取节点并获取 npm。
sure you're getting the latest versions
of these, and get nodejs and get npm.
现在我们可以把这个和版本联系起来
Now we could tie this to versions, for
现在我要告诉你怎么这么做
now I'm just gonna show
you how to do it this way.
现在我觉得我们要这么做才是最需要做的
Cool and for now I think that's actually
all we need to do to get all this running,
我觉得我们没必要再做其他事了
I don't think we need to do anything else.
让我们再试一次
And let's try this again.
我们得建个建筑
We have to run a build.
所以它能很快地做到这一点。
So it's actually able to do this
pretty quickly it looks like.
再一次，如果我们仔细看看，这应该已经足够了。
And again, this probably should be
enough that if we took a look at it.
我们来做我的 " 节点 " 应用程序。
Let's just do my-node-app.
就在那儿
Right there.
我们大概有 85人了
We're up to about 85.
我想这听起来是对的
I guess that sounds about right.
实际上，让我们重新启动整个 Docker 文件。
So let's actually just restart
this entire Docker file.
好吧好吧
All right.
所以我们只加 FROM alpine 3.10
So we just add the FROM alpine:3.10,
RUN apk，节点 npm ，我们将再次运行此程序。
RUN apk, node npm and
we're gonna run this again.
现在，如果我们检查，看看这到底是什么，所以这就结束了，
And now, if we inspect, take a look at
what this is, so this ends up being,
就会有五十兆字节
there you go, about 50 megabytes.
只为了让阿尔卑斯和 NodeJs 和 NPM 都在同一个盒子里
Just to get Alpine and NodeJs and
NPM, all on the same box.
现在，在缺省情况下， Alpine 不必安装节点用户。
Now, Alpine by default, doesn't
necessarily have the node user installed.
这就是节点分发给我们的
That was something that the node
distribution is doing for us,
所以我们得为自己做所以我们要做的是 RUN addgroup-S
so we have to do that for ourselves,
so we're gonna do RUN addgroup-S.
这也是我自己永远无法记住的事情。
Again, this is something I
could never remember by myself.
我总是需要 Google，如何将用户添加到 LINUX。
I always have to Google,
how do I add user to LINUX.
我不知道我从来都不记得
I don't know,
it's just never something I can remember.
这样我们就能复制他们的最佳做法
So we're gonna just copy their best
practices and we're gonna add a user
称为节点，我们将添加用户 -S 节点，并在组节点中添加。
called node and we're going to add
user -S node, and in the group node.
现在，这增加了一个用户叫做节点。
So now, this has added a user called node.
这里我们可以说 USER 节点。
And here we can say USER node.
这是我们可以说的建筑。
And here we can say build.
我错过了吗
Did I miss one?
阿杜瑟对不起
Adduser, sorry.
阿德瑟在那儿
Adduser right there.
这是未找到的添加。
This was saying add not found.
太好了
It's adduser.
好了现在再试一次
All right, now try it again.
好了好了
There we go.
现在，如果我说，节点应用就在那里，
Now if I say, node app right there, and
我说 whoamI ，应该说节点，凉爽。
I say whoamI, should say node, cool.
>> Brian，您在哪里指定要获取的节点版本 ?
&gt;&gt; Brian, where did you specify what
version of node do you wanna get?
> 所以，我没有，你会用 apk 来做。
&gt;&gt; So, I didn't,
here you would do it with apk.
现在我们不用担心这件事你会
Just for now we're not gonna worry about
it cuz this is something that you would
从来没做过
never really do.
但我们可以看到它的版本。
But we can see what version it is.
所以我们可以说节点-- 版本。
So we can say node-- version.
但愿是 12个，不， 10个。
Hopefully it's 12, no, it's 10.
我觉得这里有一些命名法
And I think there is some nomenclature for
啊，这个，你比如说十点十六，什么的。
this, you would say like,
at 10.16 or something like that.
我并不确定。
I am not actually sure.
但它会在那里
But it would be in there.
这也是阿尔卑斯的情况，所以我根本不认识阿尔派恩。
Again this is from Alpine, so
I don't know Alpine at all.
所以现在是你想回去的地方
So, Now is wherever you wanna go back and
加上之前我们的所有东西都是 USER 节点
add all of our stuff back that we
had before which is USER node,
RUN mkdir /home/node/ 代码。
RUN mkdir /home/node/code.
然后，您要执行 WORKDIR /home/node/code，
Then you wanna do WORKDIR /home/node/code,
COPY chown 节点节点包。
COPY chown node node pack.
我是说你可以从我们过去的最后一个
I mean, you can literally copy this
from the last one that we used to have,
包 lock.json package.json 。
package lock.json package.json.
我要把它复制到 ./.
I'm gonna copy that to ./.
那我们就去拉联合国的保监处
Then we're going to RUN npm CI.
如你所见，空格完全是任意的。
As you can see here,
whitespace is totally arbitrary.
我没有理由去做我现在正在做的事
And I have no good reason for
any of it that I'm doing right now.
我说的是 COPY --chown node:node 和.
And I'm saying COPY --chown node:node,
and.
将其他所有内容复制到同一目录中。
to copy everything else
into the same directory.
我要说的是 CMD 节点 index.js。
I'm going to say CMD node index.js.
所以，让我们回去再建这个。
So, let's go back and build this again.
我们来做吧
And let's run it.
那么链接。
So the link.
我们走了还在跑
There we go, still running but
有一个阿尔卑斯的集装箱我们将继续建造自己
with a Alpine container that we're
continuing to build ourselves.
这么说和做了，看看我们是否真正拯救了自己的空间，
So all said and done, to see if we
actually saved yourself any space,
我不确定我们是否做到了
I'm not actually sure we did.
Docker 检查 my-node-app。
Docker inspect my-node-app.
管道到 jq 可以获得一些颜色，因为这容易阅读。
Pipe to jq to get some colors
because it's a lot easier to read.
好了好了
There you go.
所以我们下降到大约 56 兆字节。
So we got down to about 56 megabytes-ish.
我们可以更低了
We can go lower.
[ 笑声]
[LAUGH]